<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>A public website of Urdaneta City University</description>
    <link>//</link>
    <atom:link href="//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 13:32:35 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 13:32:35 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>CABA crowned champion in dance tilt</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The College of Accountancy and Business Administration (CABA) won the championship award in the intercollegiate Dance Sport competition held today at the Urdaneta City University Gymnasium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nicole Mosada and Rogelio Semilla Jr. represented CABA in the competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The College of Nursing (CON) won the first place while the College of Computer Studies (CCS) got the 2nd place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#52ndFoundationAnniversarry
#DanceSport
#UCU&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>//campus%20life/2019/02/07/CABA-crowned-champion.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//campus%20life/2019/02/07/CABA-crowned-champion.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Campus Life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME sings at Centennial Pang Capitol</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Lingayen, Pangasinan- Urdaneta City University Music Ensemble made a mark in the province upon performing in the Centennial Celebration of the Capitol Building with the theme “Stronger Heritage, Stronger Pangasinan” on December 15, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Led by Mr. Jonathan Lastimado, Choirmaster, 35 students united their voices as they rendered three songs, namely; “Handog” by Florante, “Si Ka Bayani” by Gary Granada, and “From Now On” from The Greatest Showman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“All the performers in the event were champions and achievers of their ventures. It was an honor for UCU since we were chosen to be part of this remarkable event. Knowing that the provincial government recognizes us is a milestone for all UCUians,” Mr. Lastimado said in an interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also added that “UCU-ME only had one day to rehearse since the invitation was not given in advance, and the UCU Executive Chorale Concert was my priority (by that time).”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Louie Ocampo, Director of the event, expressed his commendations to the group even though the choir was composed mostly of new members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is no better chorale I know who can do justice to the tribute that has been prepared for the iconic personalities of Pangasinan other than the UCU Music Ensemble. They were great as they gave us a world class performance to honor our fellow Pangasinenses.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Most importantly, their songs made me feel proud to be a Pangasinense. They are more than perfect to be part of the Capitol Building’s Centennial Celebration”, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nakaka overwhelm kasi kahit bago palang ako sa choir, nagkaroon agad ako ng chance para makasama sa ganito kalaking event,” Eljohn Villa, choir member, stated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, a former UCU student in the person of Rica Mae C. Maer was also invited to perform as one of the lead singers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nakaka overwhelm kasi hindi ko expect na mai invite ako sa ganito kalaking event. Nakakatuwa kasi naipakita ko yung talent ko sa maraming tao”, she exclaimed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Included in the celebration were the different production numbers from various artists and performing groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, one of the highlights was the projection mapping flashed at the building itself. #&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>//campus%20life/2018/12/18/ME-sings-capitol-centennial.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//campus%20life/2018/12/18/ME-sings-capitol-centennial.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Campus Life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>German doc offers nurse training; job awaits</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Former resident representative of Konrad Adenauer Stiftung, Dr. Peter Koepingger chose Urdaneta City University-College of Nursing to receive training in International Standard Nursing Graduation (ISNG) in some hospitals in Bavaria, Germany for those qualified nursing applicants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When we were started to look at nursing schools in the Philippines, I first went to bigger universities that offer Nursing. I also went to some famous universities like University of Santo Tomas, but we had the feeling that it is better to go to smaller universities to give this offer as well.” Dr. Koepingger said in an interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So, I asked the training to be standardized from CHED, so they should do the same quality of training throughout, to give smaller universities outside the big cities advantage to establish relations and earn trust and confidence. I asked who’s working from CHED as an evaluator; she recommended Urdaneta City University,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Konrad Adenauer Stiftung is a political organization that promotes European integration, intensification of transatlantic relations and development cooperation all over the world which is linked to the German Hospital Company ‘Mittelbayerisches Rehabilitationszentrum’ (MBRZ), a recognized institution that offers training facility and unlimited job opportunities in Germany and other countries in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Registered nurses and students from UCU-CoN joined in the general orientation program conducted by the UCU administration under the guidance of university president Dr. Elizabeth A. Montero and faculty members of CoN, held on December 10, at the University Cafeteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Koepingger discussed the framework of the said training program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The offer includes 4-6-year contractual period and the pre-financing of MBRZ for the full time German language courses, 6,000 pesos per month assistance for living during full-time language training, travel costs, housing costs, and 5-year practical work as fully accredited nurses in Germany with full tariff salaries minus small monthly subtraction for repayment of the pre-financing period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the basic German language courses, qualified applicants will undergo examinations designed explicitly for the language needs of the nurses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, qualified applicants shall undertake further education of nurses, preparing them for the German Nurses Graduation which will take six months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nurses will receive the same type of labor contracts as other German nurses, including protection against lay-off, health and pension insurances and a starting salary of about 2,600 € (Euro) or almost P157,000 in Philippine currency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, after the end of the contractual period, qualified nurses will be free to return to the Philippines or continue working as regular nurses with all rights and benefits like their German colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project also aims to decrease the unemployment and underemployment rate of registered nurses in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dean of the CoN, Dr. Zosima Garin said, “The UCU is very lucky because we have German partners who will be assisting our BSN graduates to land a job in Germany with no cost.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And of course, this is only the first batch of nurses who will be going to Germany, and this project will continue in more years to come. It will help a lot of nursing graduates of our institution, so we look forward to having the partnership with these German people,” she added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We became motivated, and of course, as fourth-year students, we become more eager to graduate this year, and we believe we can do it.” Carolyn Tomboc, BSN-IV student, expressing her insights about the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aspiring applicants for the training program will undergo an interview with Dr. Koeppinger on December 11-12, 2018.#&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photos by James Robert Canlas &amp;amp; BA Comm students&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>//campus%20life/2018/12/10/german-doc-offer-nurse-training.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//campus%20life/2018/12/10/german-doc-offer-nurse-training.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Campus Life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>HTM studes train in flower display</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Students from the College of Hospitality and Tourism Management (CHTM) organized and attended seminar-workshop on flower arrangement titled, “December Ikebana: A Petal, Leaf, and Stem Sculpture by Master DC” held on December 10, 2018 at the University Gym.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Event organizers invited Mr. Dandi Arjona Carao, a well-known florist and owner of DC Paper Flowers in Baguio City, as the guest lecturer of the said event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Known as “Master DC,” he imparted his knowledge on flower arrangement in revealing different types according to patterns and color combinations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also demonstrated the circular flower arrangement with the use of different ornaments such as carnations and roses, stems, and leaves; it was also applied in the workshop by the participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an ambush interview, Mr. Carao, the guest lecturer himself emphasized the importance of flower arrangement in the field of Hospitality and Tourism Management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sa field ng HTM kasi, in-demand ang flower arrangement, and flower symbolizes hospitality,” he stressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to John Alfred Gelano, BS HRM-IV and event organizer, his co-department members arranged the venue and the flow of the program with the supervision of Ms. Tricia Lyn Tuliao, instructor of CHTM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ms. Tuliao mentioned the importance of attending the seminar-workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Makakatulong ang seminar na ito sa mga bata kasi importante ang flower arrangement sa pag-se-set up ng mga occasions like weddings and parties,” Tuliao said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Kailangan naming matutunan ‘to (flower arrangement) para kung sakaling mag-OJT kami, mayroon na kaming experience at magagamay na namin ito in the future,” Neil Kenneth Tamana, BSHMCA – I student, told. #&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photos by Isiah Godffrey Manio &amp;amp; Sidjay Paulino&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>//campus%20life/2018/12/10/HTM-studes-train-flower-display.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//campus%20life/2018/12/10/HTM-studes-train-flower-display.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Campus Life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>English majors personify literary characters</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Students from Bachelor of Secondary Education major in English (BSEd Eng) celebrated the last day of the 1st Language Festival by depicting various fictional characters through tableau presentation on December 7, 2018, at the Green Home 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tableau is a form of visual presentation that requires participants to depict the story in a silent and motionless way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Five groups of BSEd Eng assembled themselves and realized the portrayal of some of the popular literary figures from the classical myths and TV series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Group number 1 from BSEd Eng-1, block 1 interpreted various Tagalog Deities in Ancient Philippine Mythology introducing ‘Bathala,’ ‘diwata,’ and other mythical characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, group 2 from BSEd Eng-1, block 2 gave a visual representation of the popular gods and goddesses of Greek Mythology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third group from BSEd Eng-1, block 3 introduced the myth of the North Germanic people in their characterization of deities, beings, and heroes derived from the Norse Mythology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story of a vengeful fairy named ‘Maleficent’ who cursed an infant princess and realized later that the child holds the key to peace in the kingdom was portrayed by group 4, another group from BSEd Eng-1, block 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, group 5, also from BSEd-Eng block 3 amazed the crowd by their depiction of the iconic local fantasy series ‘Encatandia’ and ‘Mulawin,’ featuring ‘Sangres &amp;amp; Inang Reyna’ and ‘Modern Mulawin.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jhunard Beltran (BSEd Eng-1,block 3), who portrayed ‘Modern Mulawin’ and Jane Louise Galaban Pasion, who portrayed ‘Maleficent’ won the award for Best in Costume, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The group 5 who presented ‘Encatandia’ and ‘Mulawin’ notched the first place in Best Tableau presentation, while the group 3 (Norse Mythology), snatched the second place and the group 4 (Maleficent) grabbed the third place in the same category.#&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photos by James Robert R. Canlas&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>//campus%20life/2018/12/07/english-majors-personifies.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//campus%20life/2018/12/07/english-majors-personifies.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Campus Life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project D Coders champs in nat’l android tilt</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Organized by the Google Development Group (GDG) Philippines, the Project D Coders of the College of Computer Studies (CCS) grabbed the championship award in the Social Good Category of the Android Master 2018 held last November 17 at the Tech Portal, UP Ayala Land TechnoHub, Quezon City, Philippines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dubbed as “ElemixAr”, Bachelor of Science in Information Technology (BSIT) students namely Analyn P. Jadia, Paul Jenrice H. Tan, and Jefferson C. Macabio developed this application with the help of their coach, Mr. Danilo B. Dorado, LPT, MIT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, the team sacked various awards such as the Best Presenters, the Best Booth of the Year, and the Most Downloaded Application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“One for all, all for one; we need to give our best dahil mahal namin ang UCU (Urdaneta City University) and as much as possible, we want to put our university on the top — na ang magagaling na programmers ay hindi lang sa Manila matatagpuan kun’di mayroon din tayong humble university, which is UCU, na kaya ding makipagsabayan,” said Mr. Dorado in an interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ElemixAr is an android-based augmented reality learning environment intended for chemistry subject where learning chemical elements is beyond limits. This application aims to intensify the science learning of all Filipino students and boosts their confidence in learning chemistry, making it more interactive and interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nakakatuwa at nakaka-proud dahil naglalakihang universities ‘yong mga kalaban namin pero kami ‘yong tinanghal na champion; all our sacrifices were eventually paid off,” said Jadia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last 2016 and 2017, it can be recalled that UCU also garnered the spotlight in developing android applications with its applications “Nutrivision” and “DashFun”, respectively, where the latter was hailed as champion and the Most Downloaded Application, and the former entered the Top 5 finalists and was declared the Most Downloaded Application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The success of this project is not an individual achievement, but [an] achievement of all,” said Mrs. Rubilyn R. Nonales, LPT, MIT, Dean of the CCS, in an interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, placing second and third place were Cebu Institute of Technology University and Malayan Colleges Laguna with their applications “AEON” and “Signus”, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main objective of the said event is to encourage IT students to develop application to be published and marketed on the Google Play Store that will gauge the needs of society.#&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>//campus%20life/2018/11/16/project-d-coders-champion.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//campus%20life/2018/11/16/project-d-coders-champion.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>campus life</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
